With the Daihaseisai underway, Academy City is full of activity.
（上条(かみじょう)）
大覇星祭でにぎわう学園都市
その隙を突いて 聖人を
一撃で葬る霊装 刺突杭剣(スタブソード)の―
Using that opportunity, a trade for "Stab Sword", a spiritual weapon capable of killing Saints in one blow, is taking place.
取り引きが行われるという
運び屋の名はオリアナ＝トムソン
The name of the courier is Oriana Thomson.
And I just happened to stumble across someone who seems to be her...
偶然にも それらしき人物と
接触してしまった俺は…
～♪
#09 Route Disturb
Trace Sealer
Hello, Kami-yan.
（土御門(つちみかど)）
どうも カミやん
I'm at the spot where Oriana may make the trade—
こっちは今 オリアナが
取り引きに使いそうなスポットを…
（上条）
土御門…
Tsuchimikado...
I just shook hands with someone, and my Imagine Breaker destroyed something.
俺が ある人物と握手した途端に
幻想殺し(イマジンブレイカー)が何かを壊したんだ
I don't know what I destroyed, but she doesn't seem to be a student...
（上条）
何かってのは分からないけど
そいつは学生っぽくないっていうか
Is she carrying anything big?
（土御門）
何か大きな荷物を
持ってなかったか？
Yeah, she's carrying what looks to be a display board.
（上条）
ああ　看板みたいな物を持ってる
Where are you right now, Kami-yan?
（土御門）
カミやん 今どこにいるんだ？
I'm following her at the moment.
今 そいつをつけてる
I'll send you my GPS coordinates, so use that to find me.
ここのＧＰＳコードを送るから
そっちでサーチしてくれ
ハッ… 気づかれた
She noticed me!
ウワッ！
（上条）あっ…
（土御門）どれだ？　カミやん
Who is it, Kami-yan?
Uh... she's that blonde woman wearing work clothes.
あの作業服を着ている金髪の女
Those two sure are pros.
（ｵﾘｱﾅ）
あの２人 プロね
I agreed not to use my magic while in town, but I can't underestimate them.
街なかじゃ
手は出せないって話だったけど
甘くはできてないわね
Looks like her path has changed now.
なんか行動パターンがズレてるにゃ
考えが変わったか？
Did she change her mind?
ハァハァ… バスターミナルか
A bus terminal?
It's a maintenance area for automatic buses.
自律バスの整備場だ
A trap?!
トラップか　伏せろ カミやん！
Get down, Kami-yan!
Your turn to shine.
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）君の出番だ
（上条）ウワッ！
Quit screwing around!
ふざけんな！
Actually, I think this is some pretty awesome team play.
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
いや 我ながら
なかなかのチームプレーだね
Assigning specific roles allows us to understand and act better.
役割分担ができているのは
動きやすい
ンンッ… お前…
Why you...
Like I said, go do your part!
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
だから 自分の役割を果たしてこい
ウワッ！
And I said give me a break!
だから 待てって！
Stiyl, set up your rune cards here and stay on standby.
ステイルは ルーンのカードを
貼り付けて 待機してくれにゃ
こっちは運び屋を押さえる
I'll handle the courier.
Got it.
了解した
So, what will you do, Kami-yan?
…で カミやんは どうする？
It'd be safer for you to just stay here.
（土御門）
ここに残ってたほうが
安全だと思うが
俺は…
I...
Yeah, it'll be safer to just stay here.
僕としても
残ってもらったほうが安全だと思う
For my safety, not yours.
君ではなく 僕の安全だが
ンッ… ウワッ！
These are just decoys to buy time!
これは時間稼ぎの囮(おとり)だ
いちいち相手にしてたら
逃げきられちまうぞ
She'll escape if you try to take them all out!
…んなこと言われても
I got it already!
There she is!
（上条）
いた！
Kami-yan, I'm counting on you.
（土御門）カミやん 頼む
（上条）えっ？　頼むって…
Counting on me for what?
The "Route Disturb", Oriana Thomson, huh?
“追跡封じ(ルートディスターブ)”の
オリアナ＝トムソンか
Damn it!
ふざけやがって
（ぶつかる音）
おっと…
（男子生徒）
す… すみません
S-Sorry!
Are you okay?
大丈夫ですか？　アア…
Oh no, it's my fault.
いいえ
こちらこそ ごめんなさいね
This spell is "All-Direction Rational Formation".
（土御門）
この術式は“理派四陣(りはしじん)”
We'll use this to discover Oriana's current location.
こいつを使って
オリアナの位置を探索する
Isn't it bad for you to use magic?
お前
魔術を使ったらヤバイんじゃ…
That's why I'll need some help.
だから 手伝ってもらうんだにゃ
Convey the wind; not the air, but your will here.
風を伝い しかし 空気ではなく
場に意思を伝える
"Convey the wind; not the air, but your will here"... right?
“風を伝い しかし 空気ではなく
場に意思を伝える”ね
Stiyl!
（上条）ステイル！
（土御門）カミやん
Kami-yan!
Hit Stiyl's body!
（土御門）ステイルの体を殴れ
（上条）ンッ…
What was that?!
何だ？　今のは…
It felt like an anti-tracking defense spell...
逆探知の防止術式の
一種みたいなものか？
Nope, there aren't any traces of that.
（土御門）
いや そんな痕跡はないぜ
It would appear that she cast an automatic counterattack spell that responds to Stiyl's unique magical profile.
恐らく
ステイル個人の魔力に反応して
自動的に作動するような
迎撃術式が組まれてたんだろうさ
What the hell?
何だ そりゃ？
ステイルは もう―
Does that mean Stiyl can't use magic against Oriana anymore?
オリアナに向かって
魔術は使えないってことか？
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
まったく…
やっかいなものを組まれたものだ
Damn, that's a pretty annoying trick she put together.
生身ひとつで 生命力の探知 解析
Analyzing my vitality from a single piece of flesh...
Not only did she reverse calculate with ease, but she even counterattacked...
逆算に応用
迎撃までやってのけるとは
Route Disturb lives up to her reputation.
さすがは追跡封じ(ルートディスターブ)
Route Disturb?
追跡封じ(ルートディスターブ)？
That's Oriana Thomson's magic name.
（土御門）
オリアナ＝トムソンの通り名さ
Though, I seem to remember seeing this inhuman "auto-processing" method before.
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
とはいえ どうも
この人間味のないやり口に―
どこか見覚えがあるんだけど
But it can't be...
まさかな
あれを所持しているとは思えないし
There's no way she'd have it...
No, Stiyl.
（土御門）
いや ステイル
俺も同じことを思ってたとこだぜ
I'm thinking the same thing.
Seriously?
本気かい？　だが そうなると―
But if that's it's true, she's not just a magician, but a sorcerer, too!
ヤツは魔術師ではなく
魔道師ということになる
What are you talking about?
どういうことだ？
“あれ”って何だよ？
And what does she have?
By compacting magical knowledge into a container,
（土御門）
魔術に関する知識を詰め込まれ―
the knowledge itself will result in a type of magical formation regardless of the container's will.
それ自体が 術者の意思によらず
ひとつの魔法陣として起動する物
An original grimoire copy.
魔道書の原典だ
But for her to create a grimoire specifically for the situation...
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
しかし 状況に合わせて 魔道書を
作るなんて そんなことが…
That's just...
It may be an original, but it's still a rough copy.
（土御門）
原典っつっても 走り書きだ
It only has limited effects, and will self-destruct quickly.
（土御門）
限定された効果があるだけで
すぐに壊れるはずにゃ
I guess you could call it a "Shorthand."
速記原典(ショートハンド)といったところか
So what do we do about it?
それで 結局 どうすりゃいいんだ？
We'll start with destroying the automatic counterattack spell so that Stiyl can use magic again.
まずは自動迎撃術式をぶっ壊して
ステイルの魔術を使えるようにする
While we do that, there's a possibility she'll escape beyond our search range...
それをやっている間に
探索外に逃げる可能性は？
I don't think she'd take the time to set up a counterattack spell if she knew she could escape so easily.
（土御門）
速攻で逃げきる自信がるなら―
わざわざ迎撃術式なんて
組まないと思わないか？
Stiyl.
ステイル
何でもいいから魔術を使え
Use some magic. I don't care what kind.
"Divining Circle Formation."
（土御門）
“占術円陣”
This is a magical formation that has yet to be used and does not require the use of one's mana.
誰の魔力も通ってない
未使用の魔法陣だ
It responds to the energy of a magical counterattack spell and calculates the direction and distance of the spell's origin.
これは
迎撃魔術の魔力に反応して起動し
方角と距離を割り出してくれる
Now, then...
（土御門）さてと…
（上条）おい 土御門
Hey, Tsuchimikado!
If we use that once again, Stiyl will—
そんなの実行すれば
もう一度 ステイルが…
"Once" again?
（土御門）
“もう一度”？
誰が そんなことを言った？
Where did you get that idea?
We're going to do this as many times as it takes to discover the location of the Shorthand.
速記原典(ショートハンド)の場所が つかめなければ
何度でも試してもらうしかない
Why you...
てめえ…
Kami-yan.
カミやん　忘れているようなら
ひとつだけ教えておく
Let me remind you of something you seem to have forgotten.
This is a battle with lives on the line.
これは命懸けの戦いだ
Countries, or even the world could collapse, depending on the outcome.
結果によっては
国や世界が傾くほどのな
（上条）ンッ…
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）それでいこう
Let's do this.
えっ だって お前…
But you'll—
You lack resolve, Kamijou Touma.
なれ合うなよ 上条当麻(とうま)
If it can put an end to this, then it's worth the trouble.
それで全部 終わらせられるなら
問題ない
In return, find the location of the counterattack spell no matter what!
代わりに 何があっても
迎撃術式の居場所を突き止めろ
Okay!
ＯＫ　インデックスの
学園都市での生活は確実に守る
I'll also make sure Index can carry on living like she has in Academy City.
I'm sure you'd request that as well, right?
それが お前の条件だったな？
Kamijou Touma.
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
上条当麻…
It annoys me that you're here right now.
僕は 君が今
ここにいることが気に食わない
Why aren't you with her?
なぜ あの子のそばにいないんだ？
If she becomes unhappy as a result of this,
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
あの子が それで顔を曇らせたら
全部 君のせいだろうが
it'll all be your fault!
I wanted to change into this and surprise Touma, too...
せっかく お着替えして
当麻に見せてあげようと思ったのに
But he just ran off somewhere...
勝手に
どっかに行っちゃったみたいだし
（小萌(こもえ)）
シ… シスターちゃん
そんなに落ち込まないで
You don't have to be so sad, Sister-chan...
I'm sure Kamijou-chan had a good reason...
きっと上条ちゃんにも
何か深い訳があったのですよ
ハァ…
That Kamijou Touma!
（吹寄(ふきよせ)）
上条当麻め
Disappearing right when I take my eyes off him, sheesh...
ちょっと目を離した隙に
消えるなんて… まったく
うん？　先生
Sensei!
（小萌）
うん？　吹寄ちゃん
Fukiyose-chan!
What are you doing outside school?
（吹寄）
公衆の面前で
何をやってるんですか
軽い錯乱状態なら
トウガラシなどの刺激物を使って
If she's just a little dizzy, we can use a stimulus like spice powder to bring her to.
（吹寄）思考を外側に…
（小萌）い… いえ
N-No...
It's fine! It's fine, Fukiyose-chan!
大丈夫！
大丈夫なのですよ 吹寄ちゃん
Really?
（吹寄）
そうですか
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）当麻は？
（吹寄）えっ？
Touma...
Where could Touma have gone?
当麻は どこに行ったんだろう
There it is!
（土御門）
出た出た
占術円陣に反応ありですたい
The "Divining Circle Formation" is responding.
おい カミやん
地図 持ってないかにゃ？
Hey, Kami-yan!
Could you get me a map?
Don't you have that GPS map on your cellphone?
ああ
携帯電話のＧＰＳ地図があったか
Then that would put this around—
（土御門）それなら こっちで…
（上条）土御門！
Tsuchimikado!
Why do we have go this far?!
なんで
そこまで冷たくなれんだよ？
Why did Stiyl have to injure himself?
ステイルが誰のために
わざわざ傷を負ったか…
カミやん
こいつだって プロの魔術師だ
Kami-yan.
He's a professional magician.
術式に対する
攻撃耐性くらいはあるぜよ
He at least has some level of resistance against magical attacks.
Tsuchimikado, you...
土御門 お前…
占術円陣は
飛んでくる術式の魔力に反応して
The "Divining Circle Formation" responds to incoming magic attacks and shows me its direction and distance.
距離と方角を教えてくれる
Did you think I could break out something so convenient without using magic?
そんな便利な代物を魔力を使わずに
発動できるはずがないだろう
俺が
もっと まともに魔力を使えてりゃ
If I were able to use magic more effectively, Stiyl wouldn't have ended up like this.
ステイルは
こんなことにはならなかった
I know that, and you can curse me all you want for it.
認めてやるよ
だから 好きなだけ恨め
But I'm still going to find the Shorthand and destroy it, no matter what.
だが 俺は
速記原典(ショートハンド)を必ず見つけて 破壊する
And I will definitely capture Oriana and crush this Stab Sword transaction with my own hands.
（土御門）
そして オリアナも捕まえて―
刺突杭剣(スタブソード)の取り引きも
絶対に この手でつぶす
Kami-yan, the map.
（土御門）カミやん 地図だ
（上条）あっ…
北西302メートルの位置に
何があるか知りたい
Show me what's 302 meters northwest of here.
きっと
そこに速記原典(ショートハンド)があるはずだ
The Shorthand should be there.
O-Okay...
なっ… ここは…
This is...
ハッ… 中学校だと？
A middle school?!
10 minutes until the Middle School Ball-Toss Contest
At the competition grounds?
（土御門）
競技場か
It's just about to start...
開始まで間もない
既に客も カメラだって入ってる
The spectators and press are already there.
もう こっそりってわけには
いかないにゃ
We can't be sneaky now.
What do we do then?!
じゃ どうするんだ？
放っとくわけにはいかないだろう
We can't just leave it there!
選手として潜り込むしかないな
We'll have to slip in as contestants.
Are you serious?
（上条）
本気で言ってんのか？
俺たち 高校生だぞ
We're high schoolers!
There's no way we can sneak into a middle school competition...
中学生に紛れ込むのはムリが…
くそ！
Damn it!
That counterattack spell may endanger other people too.
あの迎撃術式は―
ほかの人間に牙をむく危険性もある
Huh?
Do you know what the most basic magic ritual in the world is?
世界で最も簡単な魔術儀式って
何だか知ってるか？
Touch.
（土御門）触れることだよ
（上条）ハッ…
There's a possibility that an ordinary person may activate the counterattack spell just by touching it.
（土御門）
魔術を知らない一般人でも―
触れることで
迎撃術式が起動する可能性がある
If that happens, it'll be very dangerous for them due to their lack of magical resistance.
（土御門）
そうなれば
魔術師としての防御力がない分
（土御門）相当 危険だにゃ
（上条）クッ…
Anyway, Kami-yan...
（土御門）
とにかく カミやん
犠牲が出る前に―
We have to deal with the counterattack spell before we have casualties to deal with!
迎撃術式を片づけるぞ
Got it!
（上条）
分かった
And with that...
（土御門）…というわけで
（体当たりの音）
ウワッ！
カミやーん！
Kami-yan!
（土御門）
すいませ～ん
Excuse me!
うちら これから競技なんですけど
We're in the contest that's about to start, but do we have to participate looking like this...?
やっぱ この格好のまま
出場しなくちゃダメでしょうか？
There are cameras too...
（土御門）カメラもあるのに…
（警備員(アンチスキル)）まいったな
Wow, guys.
Don't you have spare PE clothes?
替えの体操服は
用意してないのかね？
（土御門）
ああ あった あった！
でも 部室の中ですけど
Oh right, we do!
They're in the clubroom though...
Well, hurry up and go change then.
ああ　では 早く着替えなさい
It's the rules, so just let me check your IDs first.
一応 規則なので
ＩＤを確かめさせてもらうよ
あっ… つちみか…
Tsuchimikado—
Yep, yep.
（土御門）
はいはい　ペタリっと
ああっ！　こら！
きちんと手を拭いてから使わないか
Why didn't you wipe your hand before using it?!
もういい　行け
途中参加は認められないぞ
Ah, whatever. Just go.
They won't let you join if you're late.
（土御門）
ありがとうございま～す
Thank you!
おい
この格好じゃ 競技に紛れるのは…
Hey!
Are we really going to sneak in looking like this?
Don't worry, they must have spare clothes in the infirmary.
なぁに　保健室には替えの体操着が
あるってのが相場なんだよ
The next contest will be the Ball Toss
（ｱﾅｳﾝｽ）
次の競技は―
南沢(みなみさわ)中学選抜200人 対
常盤台(ときわだい)中学選抜20人による―
between 200 students from Minamizawa Middle School and 20 students from Tokiwadai Middle School.
玉入れ合戦です
（婚后(こんごう)）
オ～ホホホッ…
彼らからは
負け戦のにおいがしますわ
You can smell the dread from their side.
ああ くさい くさい
My, how filthy.
What the heck is this?
（美琴(みこと)）
一体 何なのよ…
What the hell are you doing there?! Huh?!
あんたは
そこで何やってんのよ？　ねえ！
え～っ？　常盤台中学？
What, Tokiwadai Middle School?!
They're full of powerful espers!
あそこには恐ろしい能力者たちが…
にゃ～！　まあ 流れ玉には
気をつけようぜ カミやん
Yeah.
Well, just watch out for flying balls, Kami-yan.
Okay...
Assuming the Shorthand was cast here somewhere, where would it be?
速記原典(ショートハンド)が設置してあるとしたら
どこだ？
I think those baskets are the most suspicious.
まずはカゴが怪しいにゃ
Since they're likely to have been borrowed from somewhere else,
（土御門）
よそからの借り物もあるはずだから
搬入前に外で設置できるからな
she may have cast it on one of them before they were brought in.
俺はポールカゴを順番に調べていく
カミやんは―
I'm going to check out each of those poles.
Your turn will come once we find the Shorthand.
速記原典(ショートハンド)を
見つけてからが仕事ですたい
Daihaseisai Administration Station
位置に就いて 用意…
On your marks...
Get set...
Start!
始め！
（爆発音）
ウワッ！
（生徒たち）
ウワーッ！
（上条）うわ…
（土御門）ひるむな！
Woah.
Don't hesitate!
（土御門）突っ込むぞ カミやん！
（上条）お… おう
Let's get in there, Kami-yan!
O-Okay!
土御門！
Tsuchimikado!
Not this one.
ハズレだ カミやん　次に行くぞ
Next one!
（土御門）カミやん　こっちも違う
（上条）ウワッ！
Kami-yan! This isn't it either!
あっ 危ない！
Watch out!
カミやん　俺の背中を使え
Kami-yan!
Use my back!
Quick, get away!
（上条）早く逃げろ！
（生徒）アッ！
Come on...
あんたってヤツは…
（美琴）そこまでして私に…
（上条）えっ？
Do you seriously...
...want me to take the punishment that  badly?!
罰ゲームを
食らわせたいっていうのかしら！
（生徒）
ウワッ！
…たく　あんたが危なくなってちゃ
しょうがないでしょう
Sheesh...
You were in danger, so I had no choice.
あっ… 御坂(みさか)！
Misaka!
Wait, Misaka!
（上条）
待て 御坂
な… 何よ？
Wh-What is it?
Listen Misaka, I'll tell you everything later...
いいか？　御坂
訳は あとで ちゃんと話す
But just get away from there!
だから そこから離れるんだ
はぁ？
あんた いきなり 何言ってんの？
What are you talking about now?
大体 なんで
あんたが こんな所にいるの？
And why are you here in the first place?
Explain that firs—
ちゃんと説明してからに… あっ…
ジャマすんじゃねえよ！
Out of the way!
（上条）
御坂
何も言わずに こっちに来てくれ
Misaka.
Just be quiet and come here.
（美琴）えっ？
（上条）そこは危険なんだ
It's dangerous there!
A-Are you an idiot?
バ… バカじゃないの？
I'll be perfectly fine even without you coming to save me...
別に あんたなんかに
助けてもらわなくても―
どうとでもなったわよ
And what do you mean, "tell me"?
そもそも 話って何なのよ？
Like I said, I'll tell you later!
だから あとで話すって
そこは危険なんだ
It's dangerous there!
I don't want you to get hurt!
お前に
ケガなんかしてほしくないんだよ
（美琴）
バカじゃないの？
Even so...
こ… これぐらいの競技で
そこまで心配してくれなくても…
You don't have to worry about me so much over a little contest like this...
…たく　急に変なこと口走って
驚かさないでよね
Geez, saying weird things like that out of the blue...
Don't surprise me like that...
Wh-What?
えっ なに？
Like I said...
黙ってろ　ちょっと動くな
Don't move.
えっ？　え… えっと…
Uh... um...
Oh no...
まさか… くそ
Crap, could you not be feeling well, Misaka?
そんなに苦しいのか？　御坂
熱は？
Maybe you have a fever—
べ… 別に何ともないわよ！
I'm not sick or anything!
土御門！　こっちのポールに…
Tsuchimikado!
It's this pole!
Nogi Middle School Equipment
（上条）
違った
...never mind.
上条当麻
貴様は ここで何をしているの？
Kamijou Touma!
What do you think you're doing here?
さっきは
何か慌てて走っていったと思ったら
I ran here to see what the fuss was, and I find you here?
どうして こんな所に…
とにかく 競技は一度 仕切り直しよ
Anyway, I'm calling an end to this match!
Fukiyose!
（上条）吹寄！
（美琴）な… なに？
Wh-What?
カミやん 吹寄をたたけ
Kami-yan, touch Fukiyose!
彼女は魔術師じゃない
これ以上は身がもたないぞ
She's not a magician!
Her body won't be able to take any more!
吹寄 大丈夫か？　吹寄！
Fukiyose, are you okay?
Fukiyose!
上等だ　オリアナ＝トムソン
I get it now, Oriana Thomson.
If this is how you're going to do things...
これが
てめえのやり方だっていうなら
If you're going to drag innocent people into this...
無関係な人間を
さんざん巻き込んだあげくに―
And feel absolutely nothing as you watch it all happen...
それを眺めて
何も感じないっていうなら…
Then I will take that damn illusion of yours...
てめえのふざけた幻想は…
...and completely destroy it with this fist of mine!
俺が この手で
跡形も残さず ぶち殺してやる！
～♪
Next Episode
Fukiyose collapsed.
（上条）
吹寄が倒れた
ステイル そして 土御門も
And as for Stiyl and Tsuchimikado...
If the cause of this conflict is the Stab Sword...
この争いの原因が
刺突杭剣(スタブソード)って物(もん)なんだとしたら―
Then I will destroy it, without fail!
俺は必ず そいつをぶち壊す！
Next time: Shorthand.
次回 「速記原典(ショートハンド)」
When science and magic cross paths, this epic will begin!
科学と魔術が交差するとき
物語は始まる